doityourself.com 2006-05-07

# DoItYourself.com Privacy Statement

###  [](http://doityourself.com/)DoItYourself.com Inc.  
Privacy Policy

#### DoItYourself.com Inc. and its warehouse affiliate DoItYourselfWarehouse.com Inc. have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and to disclose our information gathering and dissemination practices. Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the Webmaster by emailing [webmaster@doityourself.com](mailto:webmaster@doityourself.com). 

#### Privacy Policy

DoItYourself.com Inc. is a leading provider of home improvement and repair information on the Internet and DoItYourselfWarehouse.com Inc. provides e-commerce solutions for individuals and businesses. We invite you to explore our Web sites and find out what all the talk is about. 

#### Information this Site Gathers/Tracks

Our websites log IP addresses and browser types, but we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that users sessions are tracked, but the user remain anonymous.

You can browse our site without entering any personal information and therefore remain anonymous during your visit. However, we hope that our visitors will register with us so that we can learn more about our valuable customers. Our registration form asks users for name, email address, preferences, and some limited demographic information. We encourage all visitors to register with us in our Community Forums or our ecommerce cart.

We maintain a separate list of email addresses which are used to send our newsletters containing news about the subjects you and fellow readers have asked us about as well as our and specials. If you would rather not receive the newsletter(s), but would still like to register, you may register in our forums, but not in our newsletter.

Preferences and demographic information are used to help us improve our service and products. The more we know about you, the better we can serve you. Visitors may choose to voluntarily "Sign In", or request our Free online newsletter, use the Tell a Friend feature, complete a Visitor Survey, enter our contests, or request information from us. If so, we may on our own behalf send you Email, copies of our Free newsletters or surveys. (We will delete your Email address on request.) 

The only other place that we collect personal information on our Web site is on the order forms, which ask for billing information such as name, postal address, email address and credit card number should you decide to place an order. 

#### Use of the Information this Site Gathers/Tracks

Our Website logs IP addresses for systems administration purposes and these logs are analyzed to constantly improve the value of the materials available on the website. 

#### Surveys and Relationships

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis. 

The Company maintains special relationships, with various strategic partners, business partners, and operates several co-branded sites. For Example Socratic Inc. maintains a paid by incentives panel known as "The DoItYourself.com Advisors" at [http://panel.doityourself.com](http://panel.doityourself.com/). This and other co-branded site may gather additional information; the Company sometimes has access to some or all of the information, and the Company's partner's use of the information is not within the Company's control. 

#### Forums

Our Community Forums allow users to view without registering. We require visitors to register before posting so we can track the quantity of questions and answers, and to recognize longer standing with member status instead of visitor or apprentice. We also have a number of volunteer forum moderators. The information posted therein is therefore not in our control. For those visitors who do register, they have the ability to edit their posts after posting, receive an email when a question is answered. These choices are optional, and are selected by each member individually. The same conditions will apply to the ability to post article and product reviews. 

#### Order Form

The information that we require on our order form is only used to process your orders quickly and accurately. Your contact information is used to send you the product that you purchase and your billing information will only be used to bill you for that product. This information may be used for marketing purposes by us. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. We do not sell or distribute telephone numbers, except to the carriers involved in delivering your packages and only to facilitate delivery. Users may always opt-out of receiving future emails. 

#### Sharing of the Information this Site Gathers/Tracks

For those visitors who register with us, we may share your name, email address, preferences, and demographic information with select partners so they can present you with special offers. Though, as mentioned above, you may tell us that you don't want your information shared, in which case we will of course respect your wishes. Please see the Opt-out section below. The information that you submit on the order form (contact and billing information) is never shared with any third parties, including our partners. 

#### Security

When you place an order online, your personal information and credit card information are scrambled using encryption technology before being sent over the Internet. This makes it virtually impossible for your information to be stolen or intercepted while being transferred through cyberspace. When we receive your order, it is kept encrypted behind a firewall until we're ready to process it. In addition, we erase most of your credit card information from our web site database so it is therefore safe from "hackers." 

#### Links and Linked Sites

Our website contains links which may including framing in of pages from other Web sites we have selected. We also maintain a database where visitors can post Community Links. This area includes a visitor rating system. 

Please be aware that our privacy policy does not apply to these linked sites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement whenever interacting with any Web site.  

#### Cookies

Our site uses cookies to keep track referrals and items in our shopping cart system and to provide our visitors with a tailored user experience. With the help of cookies, we can present customized content and ads that will be of more interest. We also use cookies in our Community Forums to remember members passwords so they don't have to re-enter them each time they visit the site. You have the option of setting your browser to reject cookies. However, if certain cookies that track your purchase are rejected then we won't be able to keep items in your cart from visit to visit and you will have to reenter some information on every visit. We do not maintain credit card numbers between visits. 

#### Advertiser Cookies

You may be served cookies from our advertisers or their advertising agencies while visiting our site. We do not control, nor do we have access to any of the information they may collect. 

#### Opt-out Policy, Correcting and Updating

If at any time after registering, you change your mind about receiving the newsletter or sharing your information with third parties, you may visit the site and unsubscribe automatically from the link on every content page. You may also use this feature to delete an old email address or add a new one. 

#### General Advice

Finally, although DoItYourself.com Inc. and its warehouse affiliate DoItYourselfWarehouse.com Inc. have a very strong Privacy Protection policy on our end, and do their utmost to protect privacy of all visitors, we bear no responsibility for anyone else's conduct with respect to material you transmit.  As is true with ANY Internet usage and access to ANY Website, if you are using someone else's computer, or someone else has access to your computer, or spy ware is resident on your computer, or you are using a corporate or other "network", it may be possible for that "someone else" or the "network" operator to retrieve copies of Email you sent from the computer and/or to trace the places you have been visiting on the Internet. 

#### Amendments

We may amend this Privacy Policy on a prospective basis (i.e., for future visits) at any time by posting a revised policy on our Web site. Further, nothing in this Privacy Policy is designed to protect the privacy of visitors whose use of the Company's Website is, in our opinion, or that of our attorneys or affiliates is intended for illegal, improper or abusive purposes, for purposes of marketing or solicitation, or would violate any other terms and conditions relating to use of the Web site. 

This Privacy Statement is effective September 19, 2001 and has been updated on July 25, 2005.
